

Phoenix. Arizona

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary.

A passionate Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience designing, testing, and managing complex systems. I hope to work with a company that aligns with my values and interests as well as have a challenging and rewarding programming position. My main interests are UX (User design), Web Development, and writing high quality easy to maintain code. My strongest asset by far is that I am an agile learner.

Work Experience

Applied Materials Phoenix, Arizona

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Jan. 2019 - Present

- Work in the Semiconductor industry on ETL and data analysis tools. Technologies used are Typescript / Angular, Python, and virtualization.
- Focused on a high visibility web based application which is primarily used by customers to view multiple FAB manufacturing machines' Data and analytics.
- · Migrated our data analysis legacy tool to Angular 10 employing latest industry standards which highly improved the quality of the code base.
- Ingest data from data pipelines and provide the best visualizations and date tools to business users. Peer review other developers' code via pair
 programming and code review
- Got a strong understanding of programming principles (OOP, REST, MVC, etc.), as well as problem solving skills. Strong proven front-end experience with Typescript, HTML4/5, SCSS, Highcharts, and Tornado.
- Provided communication skills in multiple team environment.

Phidev El Paso, Texas - Remote

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jun 2016 - Feb 2019

- · Worked with multiple creative agencies: Phidev, Aidan James, Thrive, PRDGL Creative, and personal freelancing projects.
- Full Stack developer for various projects that includes web apps built with LAMP, MERN and MEAN stacks. Mobile applications written in React-Native, and various website built with Wordpress, Shopify, Magento or plain HTML CSS JS.
- Implemented RESTful API server and front end for multiple projects like: Insurance Selling, Logistics Company, Food Catering, Accounting portal, and Music Label Portal.
- Deploy and maintain DevOps lifecycles

Active Perception Lab, Boston University

Boston, Massachusetts

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Jan. 2018 - Jul. 2019

• Helped in research which integrated approaches from experimental and theoretical/computational neuroscience. Trying to explain mechanisms underlying visual perception in humans and replicating similar processing strategies in artificial systems. Worked on the creation of experiments with C language. Developed virtual worlds in OpenGL for data collection from subjects.

Education

Boston UniversityB.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Boston, Massachusetts

2014 - 2018

Extracurricular

Monocular microsaccades: Do they really occur?

Boston, Massachusetts

JOURNAL OF VISION; VOL 18(3). 2018 MAR 01

2018

Global App Initiative Student Group

Boston University

MEMBER

2016 - 2018

 Students help students learn how to analyze a client's needs, generate innovative ideas with a team, create a wireframe design, establish twoway communication with nonprofits, program a mobile app using object-oriented techniques, and become leaders.